Matthew Ronald Johnson

Phone: (337) 499-0872 | Email: MatthewRonaldJohnson@gmail.com

Sulphur, LA 70665 (Looking to Relocate)

Github: https://bit.ly/3e2vfq6 | LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/3sce3U7 | Portfolio: https://bit.ly/3w0kXhD

Web Developer

Full Stack Web Developer applying love of problem solving and collaboration to build exciting applications for the web. Received a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Arizona Coding Boot Camp. Proven work experience in a high pressure, quality driven startup environment. Strong communicator, problem solver, and fast learner.

Technical Skills

Front-end: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, jQuery, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, PWA, Service Workers

Back-end: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs **Version Control:** Git, Github, GitLab

Database: SQL, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose ORM

Deployment: Heroku, Netlify, Github Pages

Projects

Magic Tournament Tracker

<u>Github Link: https://github.com/MatthewRonaldJohnson/Magic-Tournament-Tracker Deployed with Heroku: https://magic-tournament-tracker.herokuapp.com/</u>

- A PWA that allows Magic the Gathering players to track their results and create graphical representations of their win rates
- Created the card search and analytics pages as well as the backend for the project
- Technologies: MERN Stack, PWA, Auth0, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Heroku

Page Turner

<u>Github Link: https://github.com/MatthewRonaldJohnson/Page-Turner Deployed with Heroku: https://page-turner-mj-ed-kr.herokuapp.com/</u>

- CRUD Application that gives users a place to create, read, and comment on book reviews
- Worked on the backend express server, added the update and delete functionality on posts, and implemented Cloudinary cloud storage to allow users to upload profile pictures
- Technologies: JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MySQL, Heroku, Cloudinary

Budget Tracker

<u>Github Link: https://github.com/MatthewRonaldJohnson/Buget-Tracker Deployed with Github Pages: https://mrj-budget-tracker.herokuapp.com/</u>

- A PWA with full offline functionality that allows a user to track their finances
- Wrote the service worker file to turn the application into a PWA and added offline functionality
- Technologies: Javascript, NodeJS, Express, IndexDB, MongoDB, PWA, Service Worker

Professional Experience

2U

Centralize Technology Tutor - Web Development June 2021-present

- Work one on one with Web Development Bootcamp students to aid them in their learning journey
- Break down complex ideas in different ways for various types of learners
- Displayed ability to work independently and manage self

Sasol Chemicals (USA)

Laboratory Technician January 2018 - December 2020

- Promoted to Lead Tech/Chemist Support during initial unit startup to implement technician workflow and actively train other technicians on rapidly changing requirements
- Collaborated with instrument vendors to develop Sasol-specific test methods for a multitude of instruments, including the Optical Control System, Density Columns, Tear Tester, and Dart Drop
- Designed and implemented polymer laboratory information management system and then trained chemists and other technicians on it

CVS Pharmacy

Pharmacy Technician September 2017 - January 2018

- Provided personable service to customers while managing other responsibilities in a fast-paced environment
- Operated under strict regulatory and safety guidelines

Education

University of Arizona

Certificate Full Stack Web Development Graduated 2021

Louisiana Tech University

Bachelor of Sciences Biology

Graduated 2017

- Minor in Chemistry
- Graduated from Honors Program with 3.5 GPA
- Awarded four-year Presidential Scholarship and highest tier of Louisiana TOPS Award
- Multiple appointments to Dean's and President's lists